PRADEEP KUMAR J K

+91-9626922811

<u>pradeepkumarjk2811@gmail.com</u> <u>www.linkedin.com/in/pradeepkumarjk1111</u> Walajapet

Summary

Aiming to shift my career as a successful and productive Data Scientist who thrives to enhance my knowledge and contribute to company's growth. Experience of 2 years in the field of Manual and Automation testing. Have in-depth knowledge in Python, Java, SQL, Machine Learning, Selenium, Natural Language Processing, Deep Learning and Data Analysis.

Skill Highlights

- Python (Programming Language)
- Pandas
- NumPy
- Machine Learning Algorithms
- SQL

- Data Analysis
- Statistical Data Analysis
- Data Visualization
- Java
- Selenium

Certification

- IITM Advance Professional Programming with Master data science program with Guvi
 - Undergone the training from July, 2022 to February, 2023
 - Project: Customer Conversion Predication
 - Machine Learning Algorithms: Logistic Regression and Decision Tree Classifier
 - o Python Libraries: Pandas, NumPy, Matplotlib, Seaborn and Sklearn
 - The project was to analysis the telemarketing campaign dataset to find the features of the target audience who got converted to a potential customer for an Insurance Company by applying the above three algorithms to find the best fit based on the metric AUROC to determine the performance which was later used to prioritize the telemarketing campaign
 - Gained knowledge in Python (Programming Language), SQL, Data Visualization, Data Analysis, Statistical Data Analysis, Predictive Modeling, Machine Learning Algorithms, Pandas, NumPy

• IBM Data Science Professional Certificate with Coursera

- Course completed on June, 2023
- Gained knowledge on Python Programming, Github, Data Science, Machine Learning,
 Deep Learning, Methodology, SQL, Data Mining, Jupyter notebooks

Experience

• Senior Test Engineer in Xoriant Solutions Pvt Ltd, Chennai from December, 2021 to July, 2023

- Project: QuickBooks for Citi Bank which integrates the Citi Bank accounts with QuickBooks Desktop and Online application for auditing
- Technology: Manual Testing, Automation Testing(Selenium, Java)
- Roles and Responsibilities
 - o Preparing features and test scenarios based on acceptance criteria
 - o Analyse of the requirements and identify which can be automated and which cannot be automated.
 - Analysis of test requirement and automation feasibility with selenium using CUCUMBER framework
 - o Developed Test Scripts using selenium web driver and cucumber framework
 - o Maintaining all Web Elements using Page Factory in POM
 - o Regression script execution and analysed the result
 - o Raise the defect and track it by using JIRA until closure

Program Analyst Trainee in Cognizant Technology Solutions Pvt Ltd, Chennai from December, 2016 to May, 2017

- Project: CURT is an Underwriting Tool to generate and renew the insurance proposals for a group of individuals
- Technology: Manual Testing
- Roles & Responsibilities
 - o Analysing the functional & business requirements
 - o Understanding the Requirements and create test data
 - o Participated in writing down high level scenarios based on user stories
 - o Going through Functional Specification Document and Low-Level Design document
 - Writing down Test cases based on scenarios and given low level document
 - o Prepared and executed test cases as per requirements
 - o Involved in Bugs Tracking and Prepare Bug Report Document
 - Used JIRA as a test management tool
 - Involved execution of different phases of testing End to End testing, User Acceptance testing and Regression testing

Education

• B.E in Electrical and Electronics Engineering from Sri Venkateswara College of Engineering from 2012 – 2016

Place: Walajapet Regards,

Date: 20 Nov 2023 Pradeep Kumar J K